# J. Michael Brown

# Full Stack Software Engineer

Beaverton, OR 97007 (503) 702-8810 jmichaelbrown.codes@gmail.com | https://jmichaelbrown.codes https://github.com/jmichaelbrown8 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jmichaelbrown/

### **SUMMARY**

Agile software delivery expert, with 4 years of front end web development experience and 6 years of software team process leadership. Enthusiastic about teaching, mentoring, coaching, and continuing to learn along with a close-knit team. Passionate about simplifying the complex and using data to inform decisions.

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, MongoDB NodeJS, Express, React, jQuery, Bootstrap AWS: Cloudfront, Route53, S3, Lambda, EC2, Cloudformation Meeting Facilitation, Story Mapping, Wireframing, Leading Continuous Improvement

# **PROJECTS**

Elevator Pitch | https://elevatorpitch.space | https://github.com/imichaelbrown8/elevator-pitch

- Summary: Collaboration web app to pitch ideas and form project groups
- Role: Concept lead, Product Owner, Database Schema Design, Developer
- Technologies: MySQL/Sequelize, NodeJS/Express, Handlebars/jQuery, Bootstrap

Grill | https://grill-n.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/jmichaelbrown8/grill

- Summary: Recipe and trivia web app, calling edamam and jservice third-party Web APIs
- Role: Lead Engineer, Product Owner, Facilitator
- Technologies: jQuery, HTML, Foundation CSS Library

Tutor Tea | https://tutor-tea.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/imichaelbrown8/tutortea

- Summary: Bootcamp tutor ratings and reviews site
- Role: Project Manager, Database Schema Design, Developer
- Technologies: MySQL/Sequelize, NodeJS/Express, Handlebars/jQuery

## **EXPERIENCE**

Nike, Inc. Beaverton, OR

Sr. Scrum Master

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

- Coach and facilitate collaboration to deliver software across 7 web front end, native app, and back end software teams for the cart and checkout experiences for nike.com and the Nike iOS and Android apps
- Advocate for the developer community by speaking at an engineering forum, coaching community meetup facilitators to create compelling content and drive engagement, and contributing code to the developer community infrastructure

- Created games in React to teach the Scrum framework and the Edge team's high-level diagrams
- Wrote Python scripts to collect and summarize team data from the JIRA API
- Created dashboards with React to visualize agility metrics and project burndowns
- Led community of practice meetups to develop agile and software engineering skills of my colleagues
- Facilitated software architecture and blueprint delivery for Architecture and Core Components teams
- Created a Node EC2 app to log Hystrix events to Splunk, deployed with an in-house automated pipeline

Eleven Wireless Portland, OR

# Software Engineer / Scrum Master

APRIL 2014 - APRIL 2016

- Maintained RESTful web services and updated SQL stored procedures for a network admin back end
- Set up Route53 entries and Cloudfront distributions for hosting customer websites
- Designed and implemented a custom content delivery network to push network access portals directly to cruise ships, resulting in a 20x improvement in page load times

Web Developer APRIL 2013 - APRIL 2014

- Added localization and mobile-responsive design to an in-house Content Management System
- Designed and developed intuitive interfaces to manage complex network tools using AngularJS

Jr. Web Developer JULY 2012 - APRIL 2013

- Created brand templates with HTML, CSS, JS, and ¡Query for custom hotel internet access websites
- Wrote a Python build and deploy script to automate portal deployment that integrated with AWS S3

Legend3D San Diego, CA

Asset Technician / Sr. Asset Technician

NOVEMBER 2010 - JUNE 2012

- Python scripting to automate movie still ingestion, resulting in fewer errors and faster processing
- Leading process improvement and documentation for the assets department

Yahoo! Music Santa Monica, CA

Library Resource / Music Director

MAY 2009 - NOVEMBER 2010

- A/V Recording, editing, and transcoding of music videos, interviews, and in-office performances
- HTML blog and email publishing for Yahoo! Music homepage and partner communications

### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

University of Washington, Seattle, WA (Remote) - Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp (expected April 2022)

**ICAgile, Beaverton, OR** - ICAgile Certified Professional: Agile Team Facilitation, Agile Coaching, Coaching Agile Transition, Agility in the Enterprise

edX/MitX, Online - Fundamentals of Computer Science Certificate

Scrum Alliance, Portland, OR - Certified ScrumMaster and Certified Scrum Product Owner

University of California, San Diego - B.A. Interdisciplinary Computing and the Arts - Music